Finding Aid for the Reverend James M. Lawson, Jr. Papers
Special Collections Manuscripts and Rare Books
- Church Affiliations
  - Pastor - Centenary United Methodist Church - Memphis, Tennessee – 1962-1974
  Engagements – August 30, 1971 – Voices of the Church in Today’s South
  Engagements – March 17, 11972 – Memphis Conference Human Relations Seminar
  Engagements – March 24, 1972 – National Honor Society
  Engagements – May 15, 1972 – Lemoyne-Owens College
  Engagements – October 11, 1972 – Kiwanis Club
  Engagements – November 11, 1972 – Women’s Society of Christian Service
  Engagements – December 13, 1972 – Leath Elementary School
  Engagements – January 29, 1973 – Southeastern Urban Workers Coalition
  Engagements – April 23, 1973 – Louisville Presbyterian Seminary
  Engagements – July 15, 1973 – Non-Violence Beyond King
  Engagements – August 23, 1973 – “A Chance to Meet: Jim Lawson”
  Engagements – November 14, 1973 – United Methodist Church Conference Reception
  Engagements – April 1, 1974 – Non-Violence Studies Program
  Engagements – April 21, 1974 – Mount Sinai Missionary Baptist Church
  Engagements – April 25, 1974 – Interfaith Conference on Amnesty-Veterans Issues
  Engagements – May 15, 1974 – Earlham College
  Engagements – June 12, 1974 – Cumberland Presbyterian 100th Anniversary
  Engagements – June 22, 1974 – Farewell Reception
  Funerals – June 28, 1963 – Vernon Dandridge
  Funerals – September 4, 1965 – Jesse J. Snipes
  Funerals – September 20, 1965 – Clarence Murphy
  Funerals – February 28, 1966 – Mrs. Stockton
  Funerals – January 27, 1967 – Robert Beaman
  Funerals – January 1967 – Helen Roberts
  Funerals – September 3, 1967 – Rosa Sanders
  Funerals – March 30, 1968 – Eddie Ingram
  Funerals – May 14, 1968 – Mrs. Ringold
  Funerals – June 9, 1968 – Robert F. Kennedy
  Funerals – September 30, 1968 – Carl Everett Johnson
  Funerals – November 1968 – Mrs. Creighton
  Funerals – January 4, 1969 – Jennie Pearl Crosby
  Funerals – January 15, 1969 – Roy Nelson Mayes, Jr.
  Funerals – April 14, 1969 – Stella Jackson
  Funerals – June 12, 1969 – Herbert T. Bradfield
  Funerals – August 26, 1969 – Mary Mildred Mapp
  Funerals – September 30, 1969 – James Wright
  Funerals – November 29, 1969 – Charles Ferguson Oglesby
  Funerals – January 31, 1970 – Henry Lee Boyd
  Funerals – February 2, 1970 – Harry Ratcliffe
  Funerals – July 9, 1970 – Velma McGhee
  Funerals – September 26, 1970 – Ethelrene Herod Bass
  Funerals – October 14, 1970 – Daniel Jasper
  Funerals – March 4, 1972 – Frank Newsom
  Funerals – April 14, 1972 – Charles Eugene Evans
  Funerals – July 25, 1973 – Betty Jean Powell
  Funerals – October 6, 1973 – Ernest Brittenum
  Funerals – April 13, 1974 – Campbell Odell Cook
  Funerals – April 26, 1974 – George Cain
  Funerals – n.d. – William A. Miller
  Funerals – n.d. – Ferdinand Taylor
  Funerals – n.d. – Charlie Hickman
  Resources
  Sermons – December 29, 1963 – “The Fantastic Claim of the Gospel”
  Sermons – December 31, 1963 – “Thoughts for the Last Day of the Year, 1963”
  Sermons – 1963 – “When Eternity Beckons”
  Sermons – January 5, 1964 – “Now”
  Sermons – March 22, 1964 – “Jesus and the City”
  Sermons – March 29, 1964 – “Responding to the Risen Lord”
  Sermons – June 4, 1964 – “Who Then is a Christian?” (a series of sermons)
  Sermons – October 11, 1964 – “Thoughts on Laymen’s Day – October 11, 1964”
  Sermons – October 18, 1964 – “The Cruciality of Acting”
  Sermons – 1964 – “We are Different”
  Sermons – January 3, 1965 – “Why Does God Forgive?”
  Sermons – August 1, 1965 – “The Witness of the Sacrament”
  Sermons – September 5, 1965 – “The Seal of the Church”
  Sermons – October 24, 1965 – “Why I Am a Christian Pacifist?”
  Sermons – October 31, 1965 – “The Sword That Heals”
  Sermons – November 7, 1965 – “The Religious Task in our Age”
  Sermons – 1965 – “Jesus Christ, The Light of the World”
  Sermons – January 2, 1966
  Sermons – February 6, 1966
  Sermons – September 18, 1966
  Sermons – December 18, 1966 – “A Sense of What is Vital”
  Sermons – December 25, 1966 – “Three Dimensions of God’s Care”
  Sermons – 1966
  Sermons – January 8, 1967 – “Pressing On”
  Sermons – January 22, 1967 – “The Seeking Church Moving Outside the Camp”
  Sermons – February 5, 1967 – “The Art of Becoming Real”
  Sermons – February 19, 1967 – “Being the Gospel in God’s World Today”
  Sermons – March 12, 1967 – “Come All The Way Up”
  Sermons – April 23, 1967
  Sermons – April 30, 1967 – “Achieving What God Affords”
  Sermons – June 11, 1967
  Sermons – June 25, 1967 – “New Forms For New Life”
  Sermons – July 9, 1967 – “The Narrow, Joyful Way”
  Sermons – July 23, 1967 – “Whose World Is It?”
  Sermons – August 6, 1967
  Sermons – August 13, 1967 – “Can A Person Hear God?”
  Sermons – September 10, 1967 – “A Dream Spoiling in the Sun”
  Sermons – November 5, 1967 – “You Are A Minister”
  Sermons – November 5, 1967 – “The Test of Waiting”
  Sermons – November 19, 1967 – “Time Enough and More”
  Sermons – December 3, 1967 – “We have Received an Unshakable Kingdom”
  Sermons – 1967 – “The Gospel According to a Black Christian”
  Sermons – April 21, 1968 – “Beyond Faith to Living”
  Sermons – June 2, 1968
  Sermons – September 8, 1968 – “How to Listen to a Sermon”
  Sermons – September 15, 1968 – “How Deadly Is Sin?”
  Sermons – September 22, 1968 – “The Thing Every Man Must Do”
  Sermons – October 20, 1968
  Sermons – November 3, 1968 – “Being Good in the 20th Century”
  Sermons – June 29, 1969 – “Finding God in a Time of Revolution”
  Sermons – October 5, 1969 – “Time For Community”
  Sermons – October 26, 1969 – “Can You Make It Without Faith?”
  Sermons – November 2, 1969 – “Are You Afraid of Jesus?”
  Sermons – December 7, 1969 – “Is Anybody Listening?”
  Sermons – December 28, 1969
  Sermons – January 18, 1970 – “We Can Justify Our Every Deed, But God Looks at Our Motives”
  Sermons – February 22, 1970
  Sermons – March 1, 1970
  Sermons – March 15, 1970 – “Reconciliation In A Broken World”
  Sermons – March 22, 1970
  Sermons – April 12, 1970
  Sermons – May 3, 1970
  Sermons – May 10, 1970
  Sermons – May 17, 1970 – “To What Spirit Do You Belong?”
  Sermons – May 24, 1970 – “Peace I give Unto You”
  Sermons – May 31, 1970 – “Toward Achieving Eternal Life”
  Sermons – August 23, 1970
  Sermons – September 20, 1970
  Sermons – September 27, 1970 – “Getting The Most From Church Membership”
  Sermons – December 25, 2970 – “The Day the Earth was Sanctified as Home”
  Sermons – January 3, 1971 – “Time As The Fire That Tempers”
  Sermons – April 4, 1971 – “Calley, King and Jesus”
  Sermons – May 9, 1971
  Sermons – July 4, 1971
  Sermons – July 5, 1971 – “Now Its Time To Take The Walls….”
  Sermons – July 25, 1971 – “Who’s In Charge Here?”
  Sermons – July 1971 – “A Black Servant Who Trusted God”
  Sermons – August 8, 1971 – “The Light That Casts Darkness”
  Sermons – August 29, 1971
  Sermons – September 5, 1971
  Sermons – September 12, 1971 – “Compassion Can Win The Day”
  Sermons – October 17, 1971
  Sermons – 1971
  Sermons – January 23, 1972 – “Where Have All The Lovers Gone?”
  Sermons – February 6, 1972 – “His Truth Is Marching On”
  Sermons – February 20, 1972 – “Getting Yourself Actually Liberated”
  Sermons _ February 27, 1972 – “The Impossible Can And Does Happen”
  Sermons – March 3, 1972 – “Count It All Joy”
  Sermons – March 26, 1972 – “Jesus and His Enemies”
  Sermons – April 9, 1972 – “You Gotta Do Your Thing”
  Sermons – May 7, 1972 – “You Are Never Alone….”
  Sermons – May 14, 1972
  Sermons – June 25, 1972
  Sermons – July 30, 1972
  Sermons – August 6, 1972 – “Guilt and Grace”
  Sermons – October 1, 1972 – “Is A Person to Blame For Not Faithing?”
  Sermons – October 29, 1972 – “Why the Church is Political?”
  Sermons – November 5, 1972 – “Discovering Jesus”
  Sermons – December 31, 1972 - “On Being Young Gifted and Black”
  Sermons – January 28, 1973
  Sermons – February 25, 1973 – “Christ Still Heals”
  Sermons – February 28, 1973 – “Worshipping The Gods of a Defeated Enemy”
  Sermons – March 4, 1973 – “Which Side Are You On?”
  Sermons – March 7, 1973
  Sermons – March 18, 1973 – “Heart and Soul”
  Sermons – March 25, 1973 – “The Lure of Mind Power”
  Sermons – April 1, 1973 – “And Intend To Lead a New Life”
  Sermons – April 8, 1973 – “The Mark of a Real Live Human”
  Sermons – April 15, 1973 – “Making Peace”
  Sermons – April 22, 1973 – “The Never-Ending Quality of Life”
  Sermons – April 29, 1973 – “A Faith For A Tough Age”
  Sermons – June 5, 1973
  Sermons – July 1, 1973
  Sermons – July 22, 1973
  Sermons – August 12, 1973 – “Going Somewhere?”
  Sermons – October 14, 1973 – “Living Thru Perilous Times”
  Sermons – October 28, 1973 – “For Wholeness, The Beginning”
  Sermons – November 4, 1973 – “God Can Also Be A Bigot”
  Sermons – December 2, 1973 – “Are You Running With Me Jesus?”
  Sermons – December 16, 1973 – “The Stumbling Stone to Faith”
  Sermons – December 30, 1973
  Sermons – 1973
  Sermons – January 6, 1974 – “The Things Through Which We have Come”
  Sermons – January 20, 1974
  Sermons – February 3, 1974 – “The Power to Become”
  Sermons – March 3, 1974 – “Jesus’ Secret”
  Sermons - March 31, 1974 – “The Fasting That God Chooses”
  Sermons - April 7, 1974 – “The Stones Cry Out”
  Sermons – April 14, 1974
  Sermons – May 19, 1974 – “Salvation and Health”
  Sermons – May 26, 1974 – “On Beginning my 12th Year as Centenary’s Pastor”
  Sermons – June 2, 1974 – “The Wide Open Door”
  Sermon – June 9, 1974 – “How Can You a Colored Man be a Christian?”
  Sermon – June 16, 1974
  Sermon – June 23, 1974
  Bishop’s Convocation on Christian Higher Education – April 2, 1970
  Centenary Evangel – February 29, 1968
  Greater Memphis Urban Development Corporation – 1970
  Human Relations Organizations in Memphis – October 1968
  Memphis Health Center, Inc. – Constitution and Bylaws – 1971
  Memphis Health Center - MAP South – 1971
  Memphis Health Center, Inc. – Minutes – 1970-1971
  Newspaper Clippings – Church – 1963 and 1973
  Newspaper Clippings – Otis Redding – December 16, 1967
  Pastor’s Report – 1965-1966
  Personal Prayers – 1965
  Publication – The Wayfarer - 1968
  Report of the Pastor – 1963-1964
  Sermon Ideas – n.d.
  Sermon Notes – 1966-1969
  Somerville, Tennessee – 1969
  - Pastor - Holman United Methodist Church - Los Angeles, California – 1974-1989
  Correspondence - Incoming – 1974
  Correspondence – Incoming – 1976
  Correspondence – Incoming – 1977
  Correspondence – Incoming – 1978
  Correspondence – Incoming – 1979
  Correspondence – Incoming – 1980
  Correspondence – Outgoing – 1980
  Correspondence – Incoming – 1981
  Correspondence – Incoming - 1982
  Correspondence – Outgoing – 1982
  Correspondence – Incoming – 1983
  Correspondence – Outgoing – 1983
  Correspondence – Incoming – 1984
  Correspondence – Incoming – 1985
  Correspondence – Outgoing – 1985
  Correspondence – Outgoing – 1987
  Correspondence – Incoming – 1988
  Correspondence – Incoming – 1989
  Correspondence – Outgoing – 1989
  Correspondence – Incoming – 1990
  Correspondence – Incoming – 1993
  Correspondence – Incoming – 1994
  Correspondence – Incoming – 1995
  Correspondence – Incoming – 1996
  Correspondence – Incoming – 1998
  Correspondence – Incoming – 1999
- Engagements (1975-1981)
  Engagements – January 14, 1975 – Inter-Divisional Task Force on World Hunger
  Engagements – May 20, 1975 – Ecumenical Campus Movement
  Engagements – November 3, 1975 – 27th Annual Minister’s Convocation
  Engagements – February 26, 1976 – Black Businessmen’s Association
  Engagements – January 20, 1977 – Inauguration of Jimmy Carter
  Engagements – February 8, 1977 – Ministers’ Institute Christian Church in Missouri
  Engagements – March 16, 1977 – Los Altos United Methodist Church
  Engagements – March 27, 1977 – Wiley College Alumni
  Engagements – April 30, 1977 – Metropolitan Urban Mission Multi-Versity
  Engagements – November 17, 1977 – National Conference on the Church and Social Action
  Engagements – January 29, 1978 – Hawthorne United Methodist Church
  Engagements – March 4, 1978 – The 50’s: Impact of an Era
  Engagements – May 7, 1978 - Wiley College
  Engagements – September 5, 1978 – National Black Pastor’s Consultation
  Engagements – September 19, 1978 – La Puente/Industry Kiwanis Club
  Engagements – September 7, 1979 – Church of the Brethren Symposium on Urban Ministry
  Engagements – November 1, 1979 – United Methodist Women
  Engagements – February 5, 1980 – 1979 Kilgore Award
  Engagements – February 15, 1980 – Grambling State University
  Engagements – February 16, 1980 – Young People’s Convention
  Engagements – June 7, 1980 – Black Agenda
  Engagements – June 7, 1980 – Celebration Honoring Bishop and Mrs. Charles F. Golden
  Engagements – August 11, 1980 – Democratic National Convention
  Engagements – January 15, 1981 – Martin Luther King, Jr. Speech
  Engagements – January 26, 1981 – Iliff Week of Lectures
  Engagements – February 24, 1981 – The Black Church and the Politics of Liberation
  Engagements – September 20, 1981 – Pastor’s Retreat
  Engagements – September 26, 1981 – World Hunger Conference
  Engagements – October 24, 1981 – Peace March
  Engagements – October 25, 1981 – University of Chicago
  Engagements – October 26, 1981 – California Lutheran College
  Engagements – November 16, 1981 – Integration and Education
  Engagements – December 16, 1981 – Memorial Service for Jerry Wurf
  Engagements – 1981 – A Wedding Service of Don Freed and Patty Ezor
- Engagements (1982-1984)
  Engagements – January 7, 1982 – Tribute to Jerry Wurf
  Engagements – February 19, 1982 – Peace Seminar
  Engagements – April 16, 1982 – A retrospective of the Civil Rights Movement of the 1960’s
  Engagements – June 17, 1982 – Los Angeles Southwest College
  Engagements – June 27, 1982 – Premiere of “The Ballard of Gregorio Cortez”
  Engagements – September 18, 1982 – Remembrance of David DeWitt Turpeau, Jr.
  Engagements – October 3, 1982 – Freeze Camp
  Engagements – October 7, 1982 – Sin and Social Transformation
  Engagements – October 8, 1982 – Service of Bishop James L. Cummings
  Engagements – October 26, 1982 – Illinois Wesleyan
  Engagements – November 16, 1982 – Post Freeze Campaign Conference
  Engagements – December 10, 1982 – Black Church Consultation
  Engagements – 1982 – ACLU Speech
  Engagements – January 11, 1983 – Baldwin-Wallace College
  Engagements – January 27, 1983 – Second Annual Human Rights Symposium
  Engagements – February 7, 1983 – Perkins School of Technology
  Engagements – February 27, 1983 – Absalom Jones’ Feast Day
  Engagement – April 4, 1983 – 15th Anniversary of the Assassination of Martin Luther King, Jr.
  Engagements – April 12, 1983 – The Church and Moral Decision Making
  Engagements – May 29, 1983 – Oberlin College Baccalaureate Service
  Engagements – June 20, 1983 – International Day of Nuclear Disarmament
  Engagements – August 14, 1983 – Peace Sunday
  Engagements – November 10, 1983 – Albion College
  Engagements - December 24, 1983 – Re-affirmation Ceremony of Bain and Bain
  Engagements – January 8, 1984 – Major Needs Campaign
  Engagements – January 10, 1984 – USU Black Faculty and Staff Caucus
  Engagements – January 29, 1984 – Pacific Unitarian Church
  Engagements – March 15, 1984 – Preview “In Name of Democracy”
  Engagements – April 7, 1984 – Pasadena District United Methodist Church
  Engagements – May 6, 1984 – Dumbarton United Methodist Church
  Engagements – May 20, 1984 – Pan-Methodist Bicentennial Service
  Engagements – October 2, 1984 – Spirituality and Peace-Making ‘84
  Engagements – 1984 – 20th Anniversary of the Civil Rights Act
- Engagements (1985-1990)
  Engagements – January 13, 1985 – Martin Luther King, Jr. Day
  Engagements – January 22, 1985 – Iliff School of Theology
  Engagements – April 28, 1985 – Holman and the Korean Central UMC
  Engagements – July 15, 1985 – Holman Discipleship Week
  Engagements – September 13, 1985 – Nebraska Wesleyan University
  Engagements – September 20, 1985 – Black Young Adult Retreat
  Engagements – January 30, 1986 – Iliff School of Theology
  Engagements – February 8, 1986 – Peace with Justice Task Force
  Engagements – June 22, 1986 – George Washington Preparatory High School
  Engagements – November 6, 1986 – Commission of the Mission of the United Methodist Church
  Engagements – January 11, 1987 – Interdenominational Ministerial Alliance of Greater Pasadena
  Engagements – January 13, 1987 – Preview of “In Remembrance of Martin”
  Engagements – January 15, 1987 – Martin Luther King, Jr. Day
  Engagements – February 25, 1987 – UCLA Center for Afro-American Studies
  Engagements – May 11, 1987 – Preaching Conference
  Engagements – September 19, 1987 – Preview of “Weapons of the Spirit”
  Engagements – October 11, 1987 – 40 Years in Christ’s Ministry
  Engagements – November 20, 1987 – Methodist Federation for Social Action
  Engagements – December 2, 1987 Salute to Congressman Augustus Hawkins
  Engagements – January 15, 1988 – King Week Festival
  Engagements – January 31, 1988 – Niebuhr Institute
  Engagements – May 7, 1988 – Pfeiffer College
  Engagements – January 18, 1989 – The Annual Martin Luther King, Jr. Lecture
  Engagements – January 17, 1989 – California-Pacific Annual Conference
  Engagements – October 4, 1989 – Justice and Peace Program
  Engagements – December 10, 1989 – Madison Heights United Methodist Church
  Engagements – January 6, 1990 – American Federation of State, County and Municipal Employees (AFSCME)
  Engagements – January 24, 1990 – Altruism as an American Value
  Engagements – March 7, 1990 – Corita Kent Peace Award
  Engagements – April 16, 1990 – Lay Speakers School
  Engagements – June 21, 1990 – El Nido Services
  Engagements – October 31, 1990 – The International Gathering of the United Methodist Church
  Engagements – November 13, 1990 – LAPD-INS Cooperation Hearing
  Engagements – November 16, 1990 – St. Joseph Church
- Engagements (1991-1995)
  Engagements – January 8, 1991 – Memorial Service for Thelma Stevens
  Engagements – January 20, 1991 – Occidental College
  Engagements – March 16, 1991 – Amnesty International
  Engagements – June 22, 1991 – Coalition for Democratic Values
  Engagements – July 15, 1991 – Justice and Peace Ministries in the African-American Religious Communities
  Engagements – January 23, 1992 – Martin Luther King, Jr. Week
  Engagements – January 16, 1992 – Emory University Worship
  Engagements – January 28, 1992 – AJ Congress Annual Tzedek Awards
  Engagements – March 2, 1992 – Senior Minister’s Seminar
  Engagements – June 6, 1992 – Marriage of Sheri Dunn and Michael Berry
  Engagements – January 24, 1993 – Mount Zion Baptist Church of Oberlin
  Engagements – April 20, 1993 – Allegheny College
  Engagements – May 13, 1993 – Easter Hill United Methodist Church
  Engagements – August 9, 1993 – “Catch the Spirit” Special
  Engagements – September 9, 1993 – Bill Robertson Celebration
  Engagements – January 23, 1994 – Prayer Service for the Victims of the Northridge Earthquake
  Engagements – May 20, 1994 – Highlander Conference
  Engagements – May 22, 1994 – Allegheny College Commencement
  Engagements – June 10, 1994 – Baldwin Wallace College Commencement
  Engagements – June 17, 1994 – California Pacific Conference
  Engagements – July 11, 1994 – Rally at the Local 660 Hall
  Engagements – January 14, 1995 – Environmental Justice, Population and the New Majority of Color
  Engagements – January 16, 1995 – Martin Luther King, Jr. Celebration
  Engagements – August 11, 1995 – Commentary of the Watts Riots
  Engagements – August 12, 1995 – Marriage of Rosalind White and Michael Adams
  Engagements – October 17, 1995 – Multi-Cultural Clergy Retreat
  Engagements – November 21, 1995 – Spotlight on the Right
- Engagements (1996-1999)
  Engagements – February 28, 1996 – Death Penalty Focus of California
  Engagements – March 10, 1996 – Interfaith Peace Ministry
  Engagements – April 4, 1996 – Day Without Violence
  Engagements – May 12, 1996 – First Unitarian Society of Chicago
  Engagements – May 18, 1996 – Marriage of Chrisandra Crowell and Danon Cook
  Engagements – June 6, 1996 – Tennessee Annual Conference of the United Methodist Church
  Engagements – September 21, 1996 – Mobilizing for the Human Family II
  Engagements – October 5, 1996 – ACLU Legislative Conference
  Engagements – November 11, 1996 – Spiritual Development Retreat
  Engagements – December 8, 1996 – A Service of Commissioning
  Engagements – January 17, 1997 – Martin Luther King, Jr. Assembly
  Engagements – January 19, 1997 – South Orange County Martin Luther King, Jr. Celebration
  Engagements – February 19, 1997 – March to the New Otani Hotel
  Engagements – February 20, 1997 – Civil Rights and Proposition 209
  Engagements – February 26, 1997 – Lenten Noonday Preaching Series
  Engagements – April 20, 1997 – Resource Center for Nonviolence
  Engagements – June 21, 1997 – Wedding of Kimberly Anderson and Kipling Davis
  Engagements – September 14, 1997 – Westside Youth Interfaith Conference
  Engagements – October 18, 1997 – Bread for the World’s Africonference
  Engagements – November 8, 1997 – Francis J. McConnell Award for Social Justice, Peace and Healing
  Engagements – November 25, 1997 – Holy Boldness Urban Convocation
  Engagements – January 15, 1998 – Oregon Humanities Center
  Engagements – April 5, 1998 – Conversation with David Halberstam and James M. Lawson, Jr.
  Engagements – April 20, 1998 – Festival of Homiletics
  Engagements – June 29, 1998 – Illif School of Theology
  Engagements – July 10, 1998 – Summit II on Sexuality
  Engagements – August 1, 1998 – Wedding of Lori Marple and Tony Pereslete
  Engagements – September 18, 1998 – Remarks on the Christian Coalition
  Engagements – October 1, 1998 – Congressional Conversations on Race
  Engagements – October 2, 1998 – Metropolitan Interfaith Association’s 30th Anniversary
  Engagements – October 8, 1998 – Changing Hearts and Minds Conference
  Engagements – November 16, 1998 – University of Southern California Employees
  Engagements – January 16, 1999 – Union of Jeanne Barnett and Ellie Charlton
  Engagements – January 25, 1999 – University of Southern California
  Engagements – February 2, 1999 – Fifth Annual Dr. Martin Luther King, Jr. Unity Breakfast
  Engagements – March 20, 1999 – Riverside District Convocation on Religion and Race
  Engagements – April 16, 1999 – Massillon, Ohio Distinguished Citizen Award
  Engagements – May 31, 1999 – The Church Speaks Out Against Hate Crimes
  Engagements – June 4, 1999 – Garrett-Evangelical Theological Seminary
  Engagements – June 9, 1999 – Planned Parenthood Clergy Advisory Board
  Engagements – June 20, 1999 – California-Pacific Annual Conference
  Engagements – September 23, 1999 – Professionals in Dispute Resolution Program
- Funerals (1975-1981)
  Funerals – January 22, 1975 – James Wilbur Haulsey
  Funerals – November 10, 1975 – Arminta Parks Sweeney
  Funerals – November 21, 1975 – Florence Harriet Taylor
  Funerals – January 22, 1976 – Roland Craig
  Funerals – March 18, 1976 – Mrs. Olive L. Poole
  Funerals – June 10, 1976 – Bertelle Lyons Johnson
  Funerals – June 30, 1976 – Katie Fillmore
  Funerals – August 12, 1976 – Ferdinand Taylor
  Funerals – September 23, 1976 – Hilda Ross Robinson
  Funerals – November 3, 1976 – Tommie Mills, Jr.
  Funerals – December 1, 1976 – William Henry Lawson
  Funerals – December 30, 1976 – Wilfred Cecil Brown
  Funerals – March 26, 1977 – Joseph D. Brown
  Funerals – June 6, 1977 – Nona Jacque Tinsley
  Funerals – June 8, 1977 – Essie Cox
  Funerals – August 15, 1977 – Oliver Edward Odum
  Funerals – August 20, 1977 – John Paul Franklin, Sr.
  Funerals – September 24, 1977 – Altheda Beatrice Smith
  Funerals – October 10, 1977 – Walter P. O’Bannon, Sr.